Guide to the Leslie Marmon Silko Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- August 2004 Acquisition, 1977-2004; 34.59; (37 boxes)
  - Writings and Related Papers
    - MSS: "Flatfoot" by Jeff Smith: computer printout of this manuscript sent to Silko (approx. 100 pp, unpg.), 1987 (Box 18)
    - Original letters, aerogrammes and poems from poet James Wright to Leslie Marmon Silko, plus the original lace itself, which became "The Delicacy and Strength of Lace" book, 1978-1980 (Box 18)
    - MSS: "The Delicacy and Strength of Lace: Letters between Leslie Marmon Silko and James Arlington Wrights:" typescript 106pp, undated (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 18)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes", undated; 12 (Box 19)
    - MSS: "Ceremony": One large group of the earliest drafts and notes with heavy corrections dated July, 1975, approx. 500pp, 1975 July; 2 (Box 19)
    - MSS: "Ceremony": One large group of the earliest drafts and notes with heavy corrections dated July, 1975, approx. 500pp (continued), 1975 July; 3 (Box 20)
    - MSS: "Garden in the Dunes": group of misc. page drafts, undated (Box 21)
    - MSS: "Garden in the Dunes": group of misc. ink drawings of plants "Garden in the Dunes": "very early version" dated 5/30/95 20258-pp "Garden in the Dunes": group of misc. ink drawings with cover letter from Simon & Schuster dated 5/28/99, 1995-1999 (Box 21)
    - MSS: "Garden in the Dunes": group of misc. page drafts with cover letter from Michael Korda at Simon & Schuster dated 11/13/95, 1995 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous "Stolen Rain" material, undated (Box 21)
    - Three original fetishes Leslie Marmon Silko created to accompany "Almanac of the Dead" with signed explanatory notes dated 7/14 (in signed box), undated (Box 21)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): ring bound script, plus production budget, project synopsis and six 8x10 glossy black and white production stills 62pp, 1981 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): early bound script signed by Silko, plus approx. 100 pages of early page drafts, heavily corrected 105pp, 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): early script in black notebook 76pp, 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): original autograph manuscript and typewritten notes and drafts, 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): split-page script (parallel visual and audio) (approx. 50pp), 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): original autograph manuscript page drafts (approx. 40pp), 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): original miscellaneous early autograph manuscript and typewritten page drafts (approx. 20pp), 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrow boy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): partial shooting script with corrections dated 7/28/80, 1980 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca" by Leslie Marmon Silko and Harry Brown: bound screenplay of this never completed film project with Marlon Brando 127pp, 1977 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca" by Leslie Marmon Silko and Harry Brown: early screenplay with corrections (approx. 125pp), 1977 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca" by Leslie Marmon Silko and Harry Brown: early film summary/ outline with corrections, bound by metal clasp (approx. 25pp), 1977 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca": by Leslie Marmon Silko and Harry Brown: script outline by Silko dated 8/15/71, plus correspondence and contracts with Black Elk Productions, research materials et. al., 1977; 2 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca": by Leslie Marmon Silko and Harry Brown: file of outlines, autograph manuscript and typewritten notes, page drafts and research materials, et. al., 1977; 2 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": original autograph manuscript and typewritten notes and drafts of this script treatment (approx. 20pp), [1982] (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller, Sundance Institute Preproduction/June Program/ Participants/1982": bound program with "Storyteller" synopsis, 38 pp (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": original typewritten and autograph manuscript synopsis, script treatment, notes with numerous corrections 32280-281-pp, 1982 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": treatment of a screenplay in narrative form dated 1983, plus variant drafts, revisions, notes, both autograph manuscript and typewritten 30283-284-pp, 1980-1983 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": signed screenplay draft with corrections, plus additional notes, photographs, playbills, el al. 81286-287-pp, 1982-1983 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": bound screenplay draft dated 6/3/82 (81 pp), plus signed treatment ("a revision of the overall structure of the 1st draft") dated 6/12/82 (23pp); plus a "Pre-History" (22pp); plus miscellaneous draft pages with changes, etc. 81289-290-pp, 1982 June 3 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": original treatment of a screenplay in narrative form dated July, 1983 30pp, 1983 July (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": bound revised treatment dated 6/13/82 86pp, 1982 June 13 (Box 22)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead", 1990-1991, undated; 15 (Box 23)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": original "typist Mamie Hicks' typed copy" including notes made in pen, 1743 pp, 1990-1991; 8 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft dated June, 1988 with almost no corrections 378 pp, 2 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) computer-generated draft, undated and marked "Yes" 429pp, [1988-1989]; 2 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft "outtake" with heavy corrections approx. 15pp, 1991 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft "outtake" of pages 827-835 dated April and May, 1989 8pp (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft "outtake" of pages 877-890 dated 5/16/89 14pp, 1989 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft "outtake" of pages 1-99 labeled "Rewrite begins October 20, 1987" with heavy corrections 99pp (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft "outtake" of pages 1-44 with corrections 44pp, [1988-1989] (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) draft "outtake" of "parts cannibalized for 1-91 version sent to Simon & Schuster typist" (pages 881-966) 85pp, 1991 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": photocopy of early (partial) draft "outtake" of pages 1-47 originally labeled "Rewrite begins October 20, 1987" but re-labeled "September 1988 page order" 47pp (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) computer-generated draft of pages 1-128, dated "June 1988" and marked "No" 128pp (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) undated computer-generated draft of pages 76-100 25pp, 1988 (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early (partial) undated draft of pages 794-857 63pp, [1988] (Box 24)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten page and section drafts, most with heavy corrections and amendations, some dating back to 1984 approx. 500pp, [1984-1989]; 3 (Box 25)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten page and section drafts, most with heavy corrections and amendations, some dating back to 1984 approx. 500pp, [1984-1989]; 4 (Box 25)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": outline of the novel (synopsis plus chapter outlines) 10342-343-pp, [1988-1989] (Box 25)
    - RESEARCH MATERIALS: One folder of newspaper clippings and other research re: "Almanac of the Dead", 1984-1988 (Box 25)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: One folder of Leslie Marmon Silko's drawings, notes of outline "maps" of "Almanac of the Dead" in colored pen, including one large landscape drawing dated 1986, [1986-1988] (Box 25)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten page and section drafts, most with heavy corrections approx. 500pp, 1986-1989; 5 (Box 25)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten page and section drafts, most with heavy corrections, approx. 500pp (continued), 1986-1989; 11 (Box 26)
    - RESEARCH MATERIALS: newspaper clippings and other research re: "Almanac of the Dead", 1984-1988; 2 (Box 26)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: Leslie Marmon Silko's drawings, notes of outline "maps" of "Almanac of the Dead" in colored pen, [1986-1988] (Box 26)
    - LOOSE NOTES: One stray folder of loose notes re: "Almanac of the Dead", [1986-1988] (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, bumper stickers, greetings cards, etc., [1986-1990] (Box 26)
  - Audiovisual Material
    Boxes 27-44 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Telarana", undated; 2 35mm film reels and several 35mm film rolls (Box 27)
    - "Telarana", undated; (4 35mm film reels) (Box 28)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 29)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 30)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 31)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 32)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 33)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 34)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 35)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 36)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 37)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 38)
    - "Telarana", undated; Several 35mm film rolls (Box 39)
    - "Arrowboy", [1982]; (3 35mm film reels) (Box 39)
    - "Arrowboy (10) 'Stolen Rain' Reel 1,2,3,4,5, & 6.", master, [1982]; 1 (Box 40, Item barcode 39002104618260)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Arrowboy", [1982]; 3 35mm film reels and 1 35mm film roll (Box 41)
    - "Telarana", undated; (12 reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 42)
      - Roll 13, virgin, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180114)
      - Roll 14, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180106)
      - Roll 15, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180122)
      - Roll 16, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180130)
      - Roll 17, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180148)
      - Roll 18, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180155)
      - Roll 19, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180163)
      - Roll 20, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180171)
      - Roll 21, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180189)
      - Roll 22, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180197)
      - Roll 23, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180205)
      - Roll 24, undated; 1 (Box 42, Item barcode 39002137180213)
    - David Amram, "Mixes", 1981 October 12; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002137180254)
    - Dave Amram, "The Stolen Rain", undated; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002137180247)
    - "Stolen Rain", 1982 January 13; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002137180239)
      Contents listed include: grandma
    - "Stolen Rain", 1982 January 15; 1 (Box 43, Item barcode 39002137180221)
    - "Telarana", undated; (14 reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 44)
      - "Stolen Rain" voice over, 1982 February 11; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002104619961)
        A list of contents is included with this audiotape reel.
        "50's D.J." Int. House
        "80's D.J." Cubero Store
        "50's" for Witch Car
        Off screen, boy running
      - Mrs. Kie v/o for opening statement, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002104619979)
      - Roll 1, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002104620001)
        Note on the reel's case reads: To: Ryder
      - Roll 2, Day 2, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002104619987)
      - Roll 3, Day 2, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180031)
      - Roll 4, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180015)
      - Roll 5, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180023)
      - Roll 6, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002104619995)
      - Roll 7, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180049)
      - Roll 8, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180056)
      - Roll 9, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180064)
      - Roll 9 [10?], undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180072)
        Contents include: wild truck, iron gate, wind trees, brook, wallows, dripping water, wind in cottonwood
      - Roll 11, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180080)
      - Roll 12, undated; 1 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002137180098)
  - Oversize
    - MSS "Rain": original photographic layouts of the Whitney Museum book (three sheets) 3pp, undated (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: "Stop Police Violence": original handmade sandwich board (in two parts) against police violence in Tucson, AZ, undated (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Original cover art mockup for "Garden in the Dunes", undated (Box 45 (Oversize))